satyarthi.org 2018-10-19

# Privacy Policy | The Kailash Satyarthi Children's Foundation

#### KAILASH SATYARTHI CHILDREN’S FOUNDATION OF AMERICA, INC.

BY ACCESSING AND/OR USING THIS SITE, YOU HAVE AGREED TO 1) abide by the terms of this Privacy Policy, as may be amended from time to time, and 2) the transfer, processing and maintenance of your personal and sensitive information in accordance with the terms of this policy. This Policy applies to information that personally identifies you (other than publicly available information) ("personal information") collected on Satyarthi.org or any additional Foundation Web property and/or third-party sites managed by The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc. or, where indicated, other information you provide to us.

#### COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Depending on the type of communication or transaction, the personal information we collect may include, but is not limited to, your name, postal address, zip code, telephone number, organization name, email address, credit card and/or bank information, or billing information.

#### WHERE AND WHEN PERSONAL INFORMATION IS COLLECTED:

Website users may be asked to provide personal information when making donations, making grants, making pledges, requesting communications, applying for a job with The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc. and/or in connection with other foundation business/programs (whether it is via the web site, e-mail, direct mail or telephone communications).

#### CHILDREN’S INFORMATION WILL NOT KNOWINGLY BE COLLECTED:

The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc. does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 18 or knowingly allow such persons to provide us with their personal information without parent or guardian consent. If you are under the age of 18, do not transmit any information about yourself, including your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address, unless you have the express permission of your parent or guardian. If it is discovered that the personal information from anyone under the age of 18 has been collected without the consent of a parent or guardian, we will destroy that information as expeditiously as possible. If you believe information from or concerning anyone under the age of 18 has been transmitted to us, please contact us at [support@satyarthi.org](mailto:support@satyarthi.org "Kailash Satyarthi Support Email").

#### INFORMATION SECURITY:

The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc. is dedicated to the security of all personal and sensitive information transmitted to us via any medium. We take all reasonable precautions to ensure the security of your information and only permit specific, designated employees to have access to hard copies of your personal information.

#### THE KAILASH SATYARTHI CHILDREN’S FOUNDATION OF AMERICA, INC. RESERVES THE RIGHT TO SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Personal information may be shared internally in order to complete your donations or purchasing transactions, to contact you about our on-going work, discuss employment opportunities and/or to discuss ways that you can further support our efforts/initiatives. Your personal information may also be used to provide you access to restricted/personal sections of our website. The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America may share, rent or exchange donor names and postal address with third parties. Except in the limited circumstances outlined below, The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc. will never intentionally share your e-mail addresses, phone numbers or financial information.

#### EXCEPTIONS:

The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America reserves the right to share your personal information in the following situations:

  1. Credit Card Transactions, Electronic Fund Transfers, Payments by Check or Money Order and Online Transactions. The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc., may engage the services of third parties to provide credit card, bank, payment and information processing services and order fulfillment services. If you choose to make an application for employment, make a donation online, by phone, through the mail or by other means, we may share your personal information with our processing service providers. We make an effort to require all third party service-providers to hold personal information in strict confidence. While we believe these other companies are upstanding and will treat your personal information responsibly, we do not own or control them and cannot guarantee your privacy.
  2. Necessity. If we have reason to believe that there has been some inappropriate interference with or use of our website, communications, charitable services or personal or real property (for example, see Terms of Use), or if we have reason to believe that one of The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc.’s website users, donors, employees or other related parties may have been injured or may have harmed some other party, we may disclose, without notice to you, personal information as we deem appropriate or if compelled by a legal or regulatory authority.
  3. Merger, Acquisition or other Corporate Restructure. We also may transfer your personal information to a third party successor-in-interest if we are involved in an acquisition, merger or other transfer of control or sale of assets.
  4. Requesting Communications. We may share information provided through our website with third parties that provide services on our behalf – for example, to send communications. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements.

#### CONTACT US TO CHANGE YOUR PRIVACY PREFERENCES

If you would like to change your privacy preferences, please e-mail us at [support@satyarthi.org](mailto:support@satyarthi.org "Kailash Satyarthi Support Email").

#### WEBSITE LINKS

In order to provide the maximum number of services and resources to our website visitors, we may contract with other strategic partners, companies and individuals. These additional services and resources may include "links" to other websites accessible from our website. The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc.’s privacy policy may not be applicable while on third-party sites. Anytime you leave The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America website, we have no control regarding what information may be collected about you, nor do we control what third-parties might do with the information. All third-party websites should have their own privacy policies, which apply to transactions occurring on their website. It is important that you review any privacy policies on third-party sites carefully, prior to using any services or programs being offered.

#### AMENDMENTS TO PRIVACY POLICY

The Kailash Satyarthi Children’s Foundation of America, Inc. may, from time to time, amend its privacy policy to address new and emerging technology, enact new security measures and to improve website functionality. All reasonable efforts will be made to provide users with timely notice of these changes. Please contact us if you have any questions about changes to our Privacy Policy.
